Have you ever noticed that a loudspeaker is the opposite of an eardrum?
你们有想到扬声器的原理和耳朵的原理正相反吗？
Eh, probably not, But it’s true!
估计没有吧，但确实如此哦！
See, our ears work by concentrating changes in air pressure onto
我们的耳朵将空气中压强的变化
a small diaphragm that will move back and forth with the pressure changes.
聚集到耳膜上，耳膜随压强变化而前后振动
This vibration causes stimulation in the heary bits of the ear,
而振动进而在耳朵里形成神经冲动
which your brain can, assuming you have normal hearing ability,
进而你的大脑能够产生听觉了
turn into what we perceive as sound.
（如果你的听觉正常的话:-P）
A loudspeaker does the opposite--its diaphragms (the driver cones)
而扬声器的原理正相反，它里面膜片（亦称纸盆）的
vibrate to create pressure changes in the air.
振动在空气中产生压强变化
This vibration gets transferred to our eardrums, so we can hear it.
这种变化传至耳朵里，我们就能产生听觉了
We’re sticking to simple stuff today because the rabbit hole is just too deep.
这里咱就蜻蜓点水一下，因为深究的话，到处都是坑要填
All you need to know is that things vibrate, which causes air pressure to fluctuate,
简而言之，扬声器纸盆的振动导致空气压强变化
which causes our eardrums to also vibrate, which stimulates the brain
进而耳膜也产出振动，耳蜗产生神经冲动
so that we can perceive that vibration as sound.
传至大脑，我们就产生听觉了
This channel started as a series exploring the history of artificial sound,
本频道一开始讲的是机械录音的历史
and it’s been over TWO YEARS since I last touched on it at all.
而我有两年没说过数字录音的历史了
Finally we’re finishing this up with the introduction of DIGITAL SOUND.
而今天，我终于要给大家介绍数码音乐了
Since it’s been forever, let’s go over a brief history of sound recording technologies.
不过录音的历史也算悠久了，我现在给大家回顾一下
The first device which could reproduce a sound recording was the phonograph.
第一台可以播放录音的设备是圆筒留声机，由专利狂魔
Thomas Edison’s invention consisted of an artificial eardrum, which would vibrate along
爱迪生发明，设备里有振动膜，随空气中压强变化
with changes in sound pressure, and with the aid of a collecting horn, the vibration is
而变化，在收声锥筒的聚合下，这种变化
transferred into this stylus, creating an up-and-down motion.
传至唱针上，唱针进而上下振动
This carves a groove into a wax cylinder,
进而在蜡筒上刻上凹槽
and the vibrating stylus creates an imprint of the sound wave.
而唱针刻录的凹槽就能体现出声波信息了
The depth of that groove becomes a literal analog of the original sound vibrations.
凹槽的深浅就是模拟了原始声波的变化
Then, when the stylus is run over the now bumpy groove,
然后，当唱针经过刻过的蜡筒表面时
the bumps cause the diaphragm to vibrate in the same way as it did
唱针的振动促使振动膜像一开始刻录时那样
when it first made the bumps, and the result is that you hear the same sound as before.
振动，进而你就能听到之前录进去的声音了
Or at least, a barely passable imitation of that sound.
至少是个差不多的近似吧
这个留声机该换皮带了:-P
Commercially produced discs and cylinders were molded from master recordings,
商业批量生产的留声蜡筒都是从母版压制出来的
and wouldn’t wear down like the original wax cylinders.
不会像原始的蜡筒一样磨损
They were played back using devices like this,
这种蜡筒要用这样的设备播放
This device is called a reproducer, and for decades,
这种设备叫唱头，几十年来
all phonographs were based on simple acoustic devices like this.
所有的录音都得用这样的机械设备来播放
For nearly a century, this is how artificial sound recording technologies worked.
近一个世纪以来，机械录音的技术就是这样工作的
Something (like this horn) would collect sound waves,
某种像这个锥形筒一样的玩意收集声波
and recreate them onto a physical analog.
然后在某种物理介质上留下相应痕迹
Then, that physical analog could recreate the original sound waves when played back,
然后，这种痕迹就能在回放时重新产生声音
While it all started with simple acoustic devices like this phonograph,
尽管一开始都是简单的机械设备，诸如这台留声机
eventually improvements were made.
到了后来，技术也进步了
The development of the electronic microphone was perhaps the most important.
其中最重要的或许是电气录音了吧
Now, sound waves cause a receiving diaphragm to move a coil of wire around a magnet,
现在，声波促使振膜振动，进而使绕在磁铁上的
SuperBart：法拉第电磁感应定律+楞次定律
想想切割磁感线，来拒去留的痛苦吧
有时是这样，得看麦克风的类型
（pingatsky:某些麦克风为电容式）
and a voltage is produced in the wire as the diaphragm moves.
线圈运动，线圈在运动过程中产生电压变化
This time, sound waves are recreated as a voltage coming from the microphone,
现在，声波被记录成从麦克风里流出来的电压变化了
and by amplifying this voltage and sending it into a new record cutting device
通过放大电压，并将其传输至全新的唱片刻录机上
which moves its cutting stylus as a function of the voltage it receives,
刻录机随其收到的电信号而移动它的刻针了
a more accurate carving of the sound wave could be made into a disc or cylinder.
进而更加精确的声波可以被刻在唱片或是蜡筒上了
This greatly improved the fidelity of the recorded sound,
这种方式可谓是大幅度提升了音质
even on acoustic reproduction devices like this.
甚至在这样的机械唱头上也是如此
With the proliferation of radio, which I feel I must explain
随着收音机飞入寻常百姓家，我觉得得提到
is a sound transmission technology, not sound recording,
广播技术，而不是录音技术了
Just so we don’t get confused too much here, the loudspeaker became a big deal.
在此我再说一下，怕大家糊涂了，扬声器是很重要的
Loudspeakers are the opposite of microphones. Instead of producing a voltage
扬声器的原理和麦克风正相反，扬声器收到电压的变化后
as a reaction to a sound pressure wave moving its diaphragm, a loudspeaker will
振膜的振动造成了空气中压强的变化，而不是像麦克风一样
move its diaphragm and create a pressure wave as a reaction to incoming voltage.
因为空气中压强的变化而振动振膜，进而产生电压变化
With loudspeakers all the rage, record players could now use a phonograph cartridge,
鉴于扬声器的普及，黑胶机需要用电唱头来拾音了
which acts like a microphone for records.
有点像给唱片特制麦克风
The movement of the stylus as the groove vibrates it generates a voltage,
唱针的振动随凹槽的变化而变化，进而产生电压
which can be amplified to drive a loudspeaker.
电信号可以被放大，带动扬声器运转
This gets very meta very quickly.
哇，这其中的变化也太多了吧
An artificial ear turns sounds into voltage,
那个迫真耳朵（麦克风）将声波转变成电信号
Dolls x1
and a cutting stylus turns this voltage into a groove on a record,
传至切割机，在唱片上刻上凹槽
Dolls x2
Then, a playback stylus playing the record generates a voltage as the stylus vibrates,
在此之后，电唱针经过凹槽后，产生电信号
Dolls x3
This voltage is then amplified to drive a loudspeaker, which causes pressure changes
电信号经放大，驱动扬声器，然后就是扬声器周围
Dolls x4
Dolls x5
in the air around the loudspeaker, which your ears concentrate down to your eardrums, and
空气中压强的变化，接着你的耳朵捕获到
Dolls x6
now your real eardrums are vibrating in roughly the same way that the original artificial
并开始振动你的真.耳膜，大致和一开始的迫真耳膜
eardrum moved in the microphone in the first place,
在麦克风里振动方式一致
Yeah,
:-P
In essence, the record becomes a way to recreate the original pattern of voltage created by
本质上，唱片就是一种恢复一开始由麦克风产生的
the microphone, so that the sound can be heard again in a different place at a different time,
电信号的东西，这样声音就可以在任意时候均可收听到了
Let’s cut out the middle bit because that’s what’s most confusing,
我们现在把中间环节去掉，这样就好理解了
A microphone like this creates an electrical signal of fluctuating intensity
像这样的麦克风通过其中振膜的变化
based on how its diaphragm moves,
产生电压变化，也就是声波中振动的强度变化
I can just amplify that signal and send it straight into a loudspeaker,
我可以直接将信号放大，然后传到扬声器里
which will reproduce the sound in real time,
这样扬声器就能实时播放了
Radio accomplishes this wirelessly, but the sound isn’t recorded,
广播是通过无线方式完成以上步骤的，但是声音并没有录下来
To capture the sound coming from the microphone to be played back later,
为了捕获麦克风录到的声音，以备稍后回放
it has to be converted into an analog of the signal,
电信号必须被转换成模拟信号
And that’s why it’s called analog recording technology,
这就是模拟录音科技名称的来源了
No matter if it’s a record, a cassette tape, an open reel tape,
甭管是从唱片上，磁带上，开盘带上
or even a wax cylinder, the sound information is recorded “doorectly”...
还是从蜡筒上，声音都是“直接”录下来的（从某种程度上）
Doorectly, Doorectly?
本翻译真的是皮不起来啊
The sound information is recorded directly onto something,
声音信号都会被直接录进某种介质上
which can then be used to recreate a copy of the original sound information,
然后可以通过这个原始介质生产很多拷贝
That something is an analog of the original sound waves,
这也就是原始声波的模拟形式了，
Improvements in sound technology were for many years simply incremental,
录音技术的进步几十年来都只是量变，没有质变
Wax cylinders became shellac discs,
蜡筒被虫胶取代
Shellac became vinyl,
虫胶进化为乙烯基
Magnetic recording wire allowed for a reusable, electronic recording medium,
而磁性录音技术的发展促使可重复录音的电气录音介质的出现
This was improved into magnetic tape, allowing for a high fidelity, versatile recording medium
而这就是磁带了，录音音质更好，用途广泛
enabling multi-track recording and editing,
而且可以多轨录音、剪辑
And to improve on the noise of magnetic tape, different particle formulations were developed,
为了降低磁带底噪，许多不同磁性材料涂层的磁带被生产出来
and noise reduction technologies matured,
并且降噪技术也成熟了
But we were still just taking some signal from a microphone,
但是我们仍然是从麦克风中读取信号
then slapping it basically as is onto some sort of physical medium,
然后大致上将其刻在某种物理介质上
And that medium was never perfect,
然而无论是什么物理介质，都不是完美的
Poorly made tape would cause signal dropouts,
垃圾英语磁带录制时或许会损失信息
Discs would be plagued by dust and scratches, and would slowly wear down with each play,
黑胶也不耐灰尘和抓痕，而且每次播放都会有所磨损
Because the analog medium contained the sound in its physical properties,
由于模拟介质上存储的信息都是某种物理信息
it was inherently prone to wear, damage, and distortion,
基本上，这些信息都是十分容易损耗，被破坏或是失真的
Which of course would wear down, damage, or distort the sound recording itself,
进而使存储的音频信息，或损耗，或被破坏，抑或是失真
If only there were some way to encode the sound,
如果有某种形式可以编码声音
perhaps a way to store sound logically rather than analogously,
兴许我们可以按照某种逻辑存储声音，而不是模拟地存储它
Maybe if the signal weren’t the sound itself, but instead were a set of instructions on
也许信号不是声音本身，而是某种能恢复声波的指令
how to recreate it, we could get lossless, near-perfect sound reproduction,
这样的话，我们就能得到无损的，接近完美的录音了
And thus, digital sound was born,
因此，数字录音就出现了
The heart of uncompressed digital sound is pulse-code modulation, or PCM,
未经压缩的数字录音是用脉冲编码调制方式编码的
注：脉冲编码调制下称PCM
PCM’s roots can be traced back to the telegraph days, but its invention
PCM的出现要回溯到用电报的时代了，但是我们今天
as we know it today for sound came from British Engineer Alec Reeves,
所知道的PCM是由英国工程师 Alec Reeves 发明的
I feel I must compliment Mr, Reeves on his given name, it’s excellent, very good,
我觉得我必须在此向Mr.Reeves表示致敬，他真是很伟大呢
He first devised this digital method of transmitting and receiving voice communication
他在1937年设计出通过数码手段传输并接受音频信息
in 1937, though it required extremely complex circuitry for the time,
尽管在当时，这需要十分复杂的电路来实现
However, PCM transmission was used during World War 2 as a way to encrypt
然而，PCM传输技术在二战期间被使用了
extremely important voice conversations, such as those between PM-WC and POTUS-R.Jr.
用于加密十分重要的对话，诸如丘吉尔首相与小罗斯福之间的
This encryption system was called SIGSALY,
这种加密系统叫做SIGSALY
“SIGSALLY”? “SIGSALIE”?
#include<SpeechCorrection.h>
Or Project X, X System, Ciphony 1, or Green Hornet,
或称为......
Anyway, Project Green Sally X System Hornet 1 was much more complicated than
无论如何，这个加密系统实际上比单纯的PCM
simple Pulse Code Modulation, but PCM was a large part of its encryption,
要复杂多了，但是PCM在加密过程中扮演了重要角色
So how does PCM work?
那么，PCM原理是啥呢?
It’s actually simpler than it might seem at first,
实际上，这个比你想的还要简单
It’s rather like a system for repeatedly asking what the instantaneous amplitude of
大致就是每秒中侦测几千遍信号中的
SuperBart:有数学微分那味了
a signal is many thousands of times per second, then simply writing that down,
瞬时振幅，然后将其记录下来
Let’s look at a simple sine wave,
先从这个简单的正弦波开始说起
If this were to be encoded on a vinyl record, the groove of the record would start out
如果这个是记录在黑胶的话，其上的凹槽先从正中心开始
straight in the center, then move to the left as the signal intensity reached peak,
随着信号强度达到最大，凹槽也就向左移动了
then it would start to move to the right, keep moving, keep moving, and then
随后，其跟着凹槽向右移动，如此往复
it would pull back to the center,
直到其回复到正中心
When it’s played back, the movement of the stylus as the walls of the groove
当回放的时候，唱针随着凹槽的边界
wiggle it back and forth will recreate this signal,
来回摆动，然后产生相应信号
这是一个1kHz的
正弦波信号记录在
唱片上的样子
And audio tape does the same thing, except the intensity isn’t recorded as a physical
音频磁带同理，不过信号强度不是记录成物理运动形式
movement, but as a degree of magnetization on the tape,
而是磁带上的磁性强度
But with PCM, we aren’t even trying to recreate the wave,
但是对于PCM，我们并不用它来恢复波形
Instead, we want to quantify it and play connect-the-dots,
我们只是想量化信号并将“点”连接起来播放
Let’s say I want to take 20 samples of this waveform,
这里我就采样波形上的20个点来举例
OK, I’ll divide it up into 20 chunks,
现在我要将波形分成20份
Now I just need to define the detail I can have within each sample,
然后我只需确定每个采样点上的位置就OK了
Let’s put this on a scale of 0 to 15,
这里我的纵坐标就是0～15了
That's 4 bits of resolution,
也就是4位位深（2^4=16）
Now, at each sampling point, we can take the closest value,
对于每个点，我们只需取选择最接近的值
This sine wave can now be represented as the following string of numbers,
现在，这个正弦波就可以用这些数字来代表了
To get the sine wave back, we simply plot those numbers on a graph,
要恢复正弦波，只需在图中标出这些点即可
Then, connect the dots,
然后连接上即可
Tada! A sine… wave?
好啦，这就是正弦波......了？
Well, a sloppy sine wave,
好吧，只是正弦波的近似了
But that’s only because we weren’t very specific,
但这只是因为我们的采样精度并不高
We only took 20 samples, and each one could only be one of 16 values,
我们只是选了20个采样，每个采样只有16个可能的值
But now we know the two most crucial parts of digital sound--
不过现在我们知道数字录音最重要的两个部分
the sample rate and the bit depth,
采样率和位深
Perhaps the most common sample rate and bit depth of digital sound is 44.1 kHz, 16 bits,
对于数字录音，最常见的采样率和位深就是就是44.1/16了
This means that every second, 44,100 samples are taken, and each sample can be
也就是说，每秒采样44100个，每个采样的可能
注：44100kHz的存在是历史原因。最早的数字录音由一台录像机+一部PCM编码器制作的
由于当时使用的是PAL录像制式，场频50Hz，可用扫描线数294条
一条视频扫描线的磁迹中记录3个音频数据块,把他们相乘，就得到了44100这个奇葩数字
one of 65,536 values, or 2 to the power of 16,
取值有65536个（2^16）
And that’s how devices like this, a Tascam DR-05, record sound,
而这就是现代录音设备录音的原理了
It’s looking at the voltage coming from the microphone, and taking precise measurements,
设备从麦克风中读取信号，并对信号进行精确测量
Every 44,1 thousandth of a second, it takes a voltage reading, and, well, writes it down,
每1/44100秒，它记录瞬时电压，并记录下来
It’s furiously quantifying and logging the voltage it measures with 16 bits of accuracy,
然后对原始电压进行量化，并近似成16位数值，存储下来
and the result is a string of numbers that logically represent the shape of the
最终，基本上能体现原先声波的一系列数字就被存储下来了
sound waves that exerted pressure on the microphone’s diagram,
也就是被麦克风捕获的那些声波
Pretty neat, huh?
挺好理解的哈
And it can actually write down two numbers at a time,
它甚至可以同时记录下两个采样呢
since this has two microphones and records in stereo,
因为这个录音机有两个麦克风，录制的是双声道
Inside this recorder is what’s called an analog-to-digital converter, or ADC,
录音机里有一个模拟数字转换器，通称ADC
The “ADC” is the actual device responsible for creating the stream of samples,
ADC实际上才是产生采样的装置
It takes the analog signal coming from the microphones themselves
它从麦克风读取模拟信号
and converts it into a stream of discrete numbers,
然后将其转换成一系列数据流
If you open the files it makes in audacity, you see what looks like a waveform of the sound,
如果你用Audacity打开音频文件的话，你会看到声波的样子
It is a waveform, but a waveform that’s been plotted precisely on a graph,
这确实是声波图，不过是原始信号处理后的声波图
Zoom way, way, way in on the waveform,
然而，对声波无限放大之后
and eventually you can see the individual samples themselves,
最终你会看到一个个的采样点
And that’s all digital sound is--
所以说，数字录音就是
it’s a huge list of numbers strung together in order,
就是一系列的数字按序排列罢了
To get these numbers back into sound we can hear, we need to use
为了将这些数字还原成我们可以听到的声音，我们需要使用
the opposite of an analog-to-digital converter, or “ADC”.
与模拟数字转换器相对应的设备
So, we’ll use a DAC, or Digital-to-analog converter,
这里，我们使用数字模拟转换器，通称DAC
I like it when names make sense,
这名字起的很直接，真是很不错呢
SuperBart: Hypo meaning low... How could I make scene?
A DAC will read the string of numbers, and generate
DAC读取数据流，并根据对应的值
an analog voltage based upon their values,
生成模拟信号（也就是电压差啦）
The DAC will smooth out the choppiness of the samples a bit to make the resulting sound
DAC还会使输出的波形变得平滑，使得输出的
a little more natural, and now you’ve got an analog signal to send into an amplifier
声波更加平滑，现在这个模拟电信号可以被放大器
and drive a loudspeaker,
放大，并驱动扬声器了
The result is a near-perfect reproduction of the originally recorded sound,
这样，接近完美的录音就被还原了
Here’s a very crude analogy to explain the difference between analog and digital sound,
以下我大致类比一下模拟录音和数码录音的区别
A vinyl record’s walls generate an analog signal by moving the stylus left and right...
黑胶唱片的凹槽通过唱针在其上左右移动来产生模拟信号
as well as up and down,
当然上下也是有的
It’s diagonally moved for stereo, but just
这种有角度的是双声道录音
imagine for a moment that it’s just left and right,
不过咱还是讨论左右横跳吧
A record directly creates the analog signal via the motion of the stylus,
唱片通过唱针在其上的移动生成模拟信号
But a digital sound source is instead sort of like a virtual stylus riding in a virtual groove,
不过数字录音就有点像虚拟唱针在虚拟凹槽里运动了
The sound samples are snapshots in time of where the stylus was,
声音的采样有点像唱针位置的快照
A DAC will then create an analog signal by running a virtual stylus through this
DAC通过驱动虚拟唱针在虚拟唱片上运动，产生模拟信号
virtual groove and placing it at exactly the correct location--
每次经过时都恰好在采样点上停留
and thus generating the appropriate voltage level--as defined by the samples,
这样就能根据采样点，来生成合适的电信号
By using a giant list of numbers to recreate sound, instead of the
通过读取一长串的数字序列来回放录音，而不是通过
physical properties of a plastic disc, the sound can be reproduced flawlessly and accurately
黑胶上凹槽的实际位置，基本上声音就能准确且完美地回放出来
with no reliance on the record player’s cartridge properties, the integrity of its stylus,
而不受播放器的特性，唱针的曲直与否
it’s motor, the quality of the vinyl etc,
电机的稳定与否，或是黑胶的质量的影响
The biggest boon of digital sound was that it eliminated all of the little nuances that
数码录音最大的贡献是，它能避免录音过程中
might change how a recording sounds,
出现的各种不确定现象
Digital sound is in a sense, absolute,
数字录音的出现绝对是个大事件
But getting digital sound into the hands of the average consumer took a long while,
但是要让数字录音飞入寻常百姓家，可是要很长时间的
DACs and “ADCs” were expensive components, and the amount of raw data generated by
DAC和ADC在当时价格不菲，而处理过的原始录音数据
sound recording was immense for the standards of the time,
对于当时的存储标准来说，是无法想象的
Although 650 megabytes, the data equivalent of the first compact discs,
当第一个商业化数字录音出现的时候
注：1.1972年日本天龙公司与NHK共同研发成功了世界第一台PCM录音机
2.现在普遍可见的音频CD正式发售于1982-10-1，由索尼在日本发售
is a paltry sum of data in the 21st century, it was unimaginably huge in the early 1970’s,
尽管650MB，一张最初的标准CD容量，对于今天的设备来说
when the first commercial digital sound recording took place,
微不足道，但对于上世纪70年代而言，这可是天文数字
For context, the Commodore 64, released the same year as the compact disc,
作为对比，与CD同年发售的Commodore 64
has 64 kilobytes of ram, and that was considered huge for the time,
有64KB内存，在当时就算很大了
A compact disc held roughly ten thousands times as much data,
而一张CD能存储比它大几万倍的数据
64 kilobtyes of CD quality audio lasts this long;
64KB的CD音质音频有这么长
About 0.4 sec.
大约0.4秒
That’s not super helpful,
这简直是毛用都没有啊
When we continue, we’ll look at the methods that were used to store data from
接下来的视频，我们将探讨存储数字录音的方法
digital recordings, and we’ll discuss the rise of the compact disc as a robust,
以及CD是如何成为强大且对消费者友好的
consumer-friendly format for digital sound reproduction and distribution,
存储数字录音并分发的存储介质的
Thanks for watching, I hope you enjoyed the video!
感谢大家收看，希望大家喜欢！
翻译：SuperBart@Bilibili
校对：pingatsky@Bilibili
原作者发布于2018年7月26日
If this is your first time coming across the channel and you liked what you saw,
如果这是你第一次看我做的视频，而且喜欢的话
please consider subscribing to Technology Connections,
你可以在B站搜索更多我做的视频
Don’t forget you can also follow me on Twitter @TechConnectify,
你也可以在推特上关注我
and you might enjoy the second channel, Technology Connection 2,
我在Youtube上也有个小频道
where I talk about stuff and don’t prepare for anything,
那个频道上的视频基本上是无台本制作
Also, thanks to Lord Telaneo on Twitter, there is also a Technology Connections Subreddit,
当然，感谢热心网友提醒
在Subreddit 上有一个频道论坛
I really don’t know reddit at all, but you will also find me there as TechConnectify,
我虽然不太懂reddit,但你们仍可在论坛中找到我
As always, thank you to everyone who supports this channel on Patreon,
还有，感谢那些在Pateron上支持我的人
especially the wonderful folks that have been scrolling up your screen,
尤其是左侧滚动名单里的人
It is with the support of people like you that I’m able to make these videos, Thank you,
有了你们的支持，我才能做出这些视频
在此表示衷心感谢
If you’d like to you join these awesome people and support the channel too,
如果你也想支持我，成为其中一员的话
why not take a look at my Patreon page,
你可以去我的Patreon主页上看一下
Thank you for your consideration, and I’ll see you next time!
感谢你的支持，我们下期节目再见:-)